<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hi, I'm George! on George Sudarkoff</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/</link><description>Recent content in Hi, I'm George! on George Sudarkoff</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 17:55:20 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://george.sudarkoff.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Distributed Ops for Distributed Apps</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/distributed-ops-proposal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/distributed-ops-proposal/</guid><description>My proposal for a talk I delivered at Velocity Amsterdam, 2016. Slides are included at the bottom of the page.
Description Up to 400 characters
In the world of microservices, when things are moving fast and constantly breaking, the accepted wisdom is that teams must own the whole stack and operate their services themselves. But how much stack is &amp;ldquo;the whole stack&amp;rdquo;? How do we ensure that operational standards are consistent across the organization?</description></item><item><title>Crêpes</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/crepes-recipe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 20:37:55 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/crepes-recipe/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 eggs 1 pinch of salt 3 tbs of brown sugar 30g of butter 200g of all purpose flower 0.5L of whole milk 1 generous splash of Amaretto (alt: vanilla extract, Rhum, any other flavorful booze) Method Batter Beat the eggs Add the sugar and salt, and stir well Add the melted butter, and stir well Add some flour until the batter gets more uniform and then add some milk to make it smooth, continue until all flour rand milk have been added Add Amaretto Let the batter rest for an hour Cooking You will need a ladle, some melted butter in a small container and a brush to oil the pan Set the pan on a medium heat Brush the pan with a little bit of melted butter (repeat every 5-6 crêpes) Using the ladle, pour some batter onto the pan while tilting and turning it to cover the entire surface of the pan with batter Take care not to make it too thick, these are not pancakes!</description></item><item><title>Scripting versus automation</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/scripting-vs-automation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/scripting-vs-automation/</guid><description>This was originally shared with the engineering org of a company I worked for at the time. It&amp;rsquo;s my stream of consciousness about the type of system my team was building at the time. Reproducing here without modifications, enjoy the chaos of my unedited remblings.
Team,
It became clear to me in the last few days that there&amp;rsquo;s not enough clarity about what we&amp;rsquo;re trying to build.
We keep talking about relatively small and specific things, but we never discuss the philosophy behind it all.</description></item><item><title>Does It Make You A Better Person?</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/does-it-make-you-a-better-person/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/does-it-make-you-a-better-person/</guid><description>Does running make you a better person? Does climbing mountains make you a better person? Does becoming a parent make you a better person?
Some people seem to believe that it does. And there are plenty of those (especially those that don&amp;rsquo;t run, climb, or have kids) who believe that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. And I tend to agree with them.
My deep conviction is that nothing extrinsic can ever make you a better person.</description></item><item><title>Buckwheat pancakes</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/buckwheat-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/buckwheat-pancakes/</guid><description>This is my favorite recipe for pancakes. I made it a dozen times in the last few months and they inevitable turn out delicious.
These recipe is gluten-free, but not vegan. And I’m not sure how I would adopt it. Also be warned, your kids are probably not gonna love you anymore after you betray their trust by serving them these on a beautiful Sunday morning.
Please note that all the ratios in this recipe are by weight.</description></item><item><title>Borscht</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/borscht-recipe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 09:21:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/borscht-recipe/</guid><description>My dad&amp;rsquo;s borscht recipe that he has been cooking for 50 years.
Ingredients 500g of beef with bones 3L of water 200g of root vegetables (e.g., onion, carrot, parsley root, radish) 200g of shredded cabbage 200g of beets 100g of tomates 300g of potatoes bay leaf, pepper, salt, herbs to taste Method put the beef in the pot and add water simmer for a minimum of 2 hours, add salt after about 1h30m cut the root vegetables into 10mm cubes and sauté in vegetable oil separately sauté shredded cabbage until soft coarsely grate the beets and sauté for 15-20 minutes, until fully cooked blanche the tomatoes, cut them into pieces, and sauté in vegetable oil for 10-15 minutes on low heat remove the beef from the pot and filter the broth then add the sauteed root vegetables and cabbage to the broth and set on medium heat when it starts to boil again, reduce the heat to simmer add the potatoes cut into 15mm cubes and cook for 10-15 min add the sauteed beets and cook for another 10 min cut or shred the beef into small-ish pieces and add back to the soup finally add the sauteed tomatoes, bay leaf, pepper, herbs and the borscht is ready!</description></item><item><title>Key Git concepts</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/key-git-concepts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 20:46:53 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/key-git-concepts/</guid><description>Understanding a few key concepts will help you make sense of how Git works and how to use it effectively.
Full history With Git, every repository contains a full copy of the project history, and no repository is inherently more important than any other.
Content-addressable Git stores content in files with names that are 40-hexdigit (160-bit) SHA1 hashes. This has some interesting implications. It means for example that Git will never store the same data twice within a repository because identical data would have identical SHA1 hashes and therefore be stored in the same file.</description></item><item><title>Fitness Proportionate Disk Selection</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/fitness-proportionate-disk-selection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/fitness-proportionate-disk-selection/</guid><description>This is a proposal I made for improving the disk selection algorithm of a distributed file storage system.
Current Disk Selection Algorithm The current algorithm randomly selects a disk among the top N percent and assigns it to a given equivalence class. This strategy is suboptimal for a couple of reasons:
Even when there&amp;rsquo;s a great variability of fitness values among the top N percent of the disks, the most suitable disks will have the same probability of being selected as the least suitable disks, thus leading to unbalanced placement.</description></item><item><title>Rock climbing lessons</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/climbing-lessons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/climbing-lessons/</guid><description>There are many lessons to be learned from rock climbing, but the following three are the main ones for me.
Don&amp;rsquo;t give up Very often giving up in rock climbing is scarier than persisting—nobody likes falling. Especially if it&amp;rsquo;s a long and nasty fall. And what you very quickly discover is that in rock climbing, like in life (or Jazz, if you&amp;rsquo;re a musician), sticking with it for long enough eventually gets you up there.</description></item><item><title>Rock climbing First-Aid kit</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/rock-climbing-first-aid-kit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/rock-climbing-first-aid-kit/</guid><description>Disclaimer: I’m not a doctor, yadda-yadda-yadda. Simply having a first-aid kit in your pack is neither going to keep you safe, nor magically save somebody’s life if you have no idea how to use it. If you climb outdoors, do yourself a favor and take a Wilderness First Aid or a similar class.
First of all, your kit should be appropriate for your level of training and for the environment you’re going to find yourself in.</description></item><item><title>Kids' activity tower</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/activity-tower/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2012 12:00:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/activity-tower/</guid><description>On January 1st, 2012 I sketched an idea—an activity tower for my yet to be born son. Cooking is a big part of our family life, and I wanted my future son to be able to participate in this activity.
The idea was to build the tower out of 3/4-inch plywood, using only a saw and a drill. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I came up with in SketchUp:
I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use the traditional joinery, like a box joint.</description></item><item><title>Markdown + Pandoc Workflow</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/markdown-plus-pandoc-workflow/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/markdown-plus-pandoc-workflow/</guid><description>Requirements This article outlines my setup and workflow for writing documents using Markdown and pandoc. This is a workflow that I personally find natural and convenient. There are some very important limitations (discussed below), but I&amp;rsquo;ve been successfully using this workflow for quite some time and it seems to be working great.
Main requirements for my workflow were:
plain text editing keeping track of multiple revisions collaboration with multiple simultaneous remote and offline authors support for multiple target output formats automated publishing (through an external build system and such) Limitations Note that publishing is a one-way process in this workflow.</description></item><item><title>Turtles in my navel</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/turtles-in-my-navel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 12:29:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/turtles-in-my-navel/</guid><description>Turtles in my navel are having an argument: “It’s not my turn to take out the trash,” hisses Greg, “why do you insist that it is?” A vein on his right temple is pulsing a steady 60 beats per minute; he manages to stay mostly calm – he loves Patricia, after all.
The sun just popped up from behind my left breast. The snails of the morning chill are chased away by the spreading beams of warmth.</description></item><item><title>Cherry Garcia ice cream</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/cherry-garcia-ice-cream-recipe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/cherry-garcia-ice-cream-recipe/</guid><description>I made this recipe a number of times and the results are always excellent!
Prep Time: 15 minutes Total Time: 30 minutes Ingredients 2 eggs 1/3 cup sugar 2 cups heavy cream 1 cup whole milk 1/2 cup crushed dark chocolate 1/2 cup fresh cherries Method Place the crushed chocolate (tiny solid chunks taste better than shaved flakes which tend to soften or even dissolve) and the pitted and halved cherries (you can use canned cherries, but make sure to drain and dry them first) in separate bowls and refrigerate for a few hours.</description></item><item><title>Salted salmon</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/salted-salmon-recipe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2005 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/salted-salmon-recipe/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 package of fresh salmon from Costco (approx. $11) sans 5 &amp;rsquo;tail&amp;rsquo; inches 1 jar of kosher flake salt from Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s (about 75 grams) 2 tbsp assorted whole pepper (black, white, whatever) bay leaf ad libitum Method Cut the pieces of salmon in half, wash them and dry with paper towels. Rub some salt into salmon. Sprinkle some salt and peppers on the bottom of the pot, and lay the first piece of salmon flat in the pot.</description></item><item><title>Palm OS is dead</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/palmos-is-dead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2004 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/palmos-is-dead/</guid><description>I was cleaning up the address book on my PDA the other day when I suddenly realized that Palm OS is going to die pretty soon! Yes, I think its days are counted and here&amp;rsquo;s why.
Programming for the Palm OS platform has a very distinct &amp;ldquo;embedded&amp;rdquo; smell to it. Memory management is a mess, supporting different screen resolutions is a major pain in the butt, and instead of a real file system developers have to deal with this stupid notion that everything is a database.</description></item><item><title>A little bad poetry</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/a-little-bad-poetry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2004 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/a-little-bad-poetry/</guid><description>As I was going through my archives the other day, I came across a few of my poems that I wrote in college (you know, everyone is a poet when nineteen). I&amp;rsquo;ve tried my hand at translating a couple into English and found it to be extremely difficult (mostly due to the lack of ability on my part), so I took it as a challenge, and attempted to translate the shortest and least rhymed one.</description></item><item><title>Programmer's Productivity</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/programmer-productivity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2003 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/programmer-productivity/</guid><description>A meditative piece in which I explore the notion of productivity as applied to the craft of a software developer (and other such crap).
Yesterday I spent twelve hours hunting down a most bizarre bug. I flipped through literally thousands of lines of code, I set dozens of breakpoints only to realize that those places were being hit hundreds of times, and it is virtually impossible to debug it that way.</description></item><item><title>Анупадака Белый</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/andrew-bely/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 1995 12:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/andrew-bely/</guid><description>СИМВОЛИЗМ Символ есть знак или ознаменование. То, что он означает или знаменует, не есть какая-либо определенная идея.
Подобно солнечному лучу, символ прорезывает все планы бытия и все сферы сознания и знаменует в каждом плане иные сущности, исполняет в каждой сфере иное назначение.
Символика — система символов; символизм — искусство, основанное на символах. Оно вполне утверждает свой принцип, когда разоблачает сознанию вещи, как символы, а символы как мифы.
В искусстве, как и везде, можно проследить влияние двух начал: мужского и женского.</description></item><item><title>Весна</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/spring/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 1995 12:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/spring/</guid><description>Фьюить-птица! Звонок! Трамвай! Перескакиваю сайгаком через лужи, наполовину заполненные трамвайными рельсами. Шум, гвалт! Люди бегут, ручьи текут. Все подчиняется вечному закону наступательного движения. Из-под снега пробивается трава. Деревья еще не распустились. Чего не скажешь о женщинах.
Остановился, задумался. Хорошо!
Отряхиваю пыль с плеч, с груди, с ног, с волос. Расправляю крылья, дышу. Свежо! Уа-уа! У-лю-лю! Фьюить!..
Звонок, трамвай, сайгаком по лужам, трава, ноги, волосы, люди, ручьи&amp;hellip; Несет меня. Впадаю в океан&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Миссия Будды</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/buddha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 1995 12:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/buddha/</guid><description>В историческом аспекте буддизм есть наиболее важная религия, хотя он не является таковой в аспекте философском. Это самое большое религиозное движение, гигантская духовная волна. Нет ни одной цивилизации, которая не ощутила бы на себе влияния буддизма.
Чтобы постичь суть учения Будды, нужно знать, что за события творились в Индии в тот момент. Необходимо понять, что представляло из себя индийское общество, когда индийская цивилизация достигла наивысшего расцвета. Легко заметить, что индийская цивилизация погибала и возрождалась неоднократно.</description></item><item><title>Розовое солнышко</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/rose-sun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 1987 12:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/rose-sun/</guid><description>— 1987 — Розовое солнышко На твоих губах Голубая даль в глазах Золото в перстах Ну а я, соколик, Высоко лечу Даль и солнце с золотом Разом отхвачу</description></item></channel></rss>