<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Self-Improvement on George Sudarkoff</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/tags/self-improvement/</link><description>Recent content in Self-Improvement on George Sudarkoff</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 12:17:31 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://george.sudarkoff.com/tags/self-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Yield to temptation</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/yield-to-temptation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 12:17:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/yield-to-temptation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oscar Wilde famously wrote, &amp;ldquo;The only way to get rid of a temptation is to yield to it.&amp;rdquo; But this quote is as profound as it is misunderstood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People believe that giving in to a temptation is a weakness. And they judge harshly those who can&amp;rsquo;t resist their unhealthy urges. Yet, they don&amp;rsquo;t apply the same standard to people obsessed with, say, sports or arts. The difference between these two is thinner than most think.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Does It Make You A Better Person?</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/does-it-make-you-a-better-person/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/does-it-make-you-a-better-person/</guid><description>&lt;p>Does running make you a better person? Does climbing mountains make you a better person? Does becoming a parent make you a better person?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some people seem to believe that it does. And there are plenty of those (especially those that don&amp;rsquo;t run, climb, or have kids) who believe that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. And I tend to agree with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My deep conviction is that nothing extrinsic can ever make you a better person. Or a worse person, for that mater. Being rich won&amp;rsquo;t make you a better person. Being poor won&amp;rsquo;t either. Believing in God won&amp;rsquo;t make you a better person. Nor being an atheist. Surviving cancer or becoming terminally ill won&amp;rsquo;t make you a better person. And even helping others won&amp;rsquo;t magically turn you into a better person.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rock climbing lessons</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/climbing-lessons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/climbing-lessons/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are many lessons to be learned from rock climbing, but the following three are the main ones for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dont-give-up">Don&amp;rsquo;t give up&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Very often giving up in rock climbing is scarier than persisting—nobody likes falling. Especially if it&amp;rsquo;s a long and nasty fall. And what you very quickly discover is that in rock climbing, like in life (or Jazz, if you&amp;rsquo;re a musician), sticking with it for long enough eventually gets you up there. If you are persistent and don&amp;rsquo;t give up, you sooner or later find your groove and come on top victorious.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dvorak, progress update</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/dvorak-progress-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2006 16:18:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/dvorak-progress-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been six months since I switched to Dvorak. My current typing speed is 56 words per minute with the average error rate of 6.4%.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is slightly slower than the 60 wpm I had with QWERTY just before the switch. And the error rate should be below 5% to consider my typing accurate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some might say that it&amp;rsquo;s a failed experiment—not only do I not type 40% faster than I did before the switch, as I hoped, my typing is also slightly less accurate.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>