<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Productivity on George Sudarkoff</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/tags/productivity/</link><description>Recent content in Productivity on George Sudarkoff</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 12:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://george.sudarkoff.com/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Markdown + Pandoc Workflow</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/markdown-plus-pandoc-workflow/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/markdown-plus-pandoc-workflow/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="requirements">Requirements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This article outlines my setup and workflow for writing documents using &lt;a href="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://pandoc.org">pandoc&lt;/a>. This is a workflow that I personally find natural and convenient. There are some very important limitations (discussed below), but I&amp;rsquo;ve been successfully using this workflow for quite some time and it seems to be working great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Main requirements for my workflow were:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>plain text editing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>keeping track of multiple revisions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>collaboration with multiple simultaneous remote and offline authors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>support for multiple target output formats&lt;/li>
&lt;li>automated publishing (through an external build system and such)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="limitations">Limitations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Note that publishing is a one-way process in this workflow. If you publish on a Wiki, then you&amp;rsquo;ll need to find a way to pull the changes from Wiki back into your &amp;ldquo;source&amp;rdquo; document. I&amp;rsquo;m using Git-MediaWiki bridge to publish/update articles to/from our corporate wiki. I&amp;rsquo;ve also looked into replacing MediaWiki with gitit which uses Git as a backend and therefore would have allowed me to push/pull to it directly, but presently the feature set is not complete enough to be a viable replacement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dvorak, progress update</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/dvorak-progress-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2006 16:18:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/dvorak-progress-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been six months since I switched to Dvorak. My current typing speed is 56 words per minute with the average error rate of 6.4%.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is slightly slower than the 60 wpm I had with QWERTY just before the switch. And the error rate should be below 5% to consider my typing accurate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some might say that it&amp;rsquo;s a failed experiment—not only do I not type 40% faster than I did before the switch, as I hoped, my typing is also slightly less accurate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programmer's Productivity</title><link>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/programmer-productivity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2003 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://george.sudarkoff.com/posts/programmer-productivity/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>A meditative piece in which I explore the notion of productivity as applied to the craft of a software developer (and other such crap).&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday I spent twelve hours hunting down a most bizarre bug. I flipped through literally thousands of lines of code, I set dozens of breakpoints only to realize that those places were being hit hundreds of times, and it is virtually impossible to debug it that way. I tried everything I could think of, but nothing helped and by the end of the day I was totally exhausted and pretty much ready to choke somebody.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>